<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-09-25T08:17:44-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Duk Lee</title><subtitle>I am currently working as a web developer. But working on branching out of it. Trying to figure out what to do with my life still.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">How much is your third of life worth?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/career/2018/09/25/how-much-is-your-third-of-life-worth.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How much is your third of life worth?" /><published>2018-09-25T06:02:18-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-25T06:02:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/career/2018/09/25/how-much-is-your-third-of-life-worth</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/career/2018/09/25/how-much-is-your-third-of-life-worth.html">&lt;p&gt;When you think about your job, you have to ask this question; is my salary worth third of my life?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am way past thinking about my passion and what not. I am training myself to think everything in terms of money. Again, money is one of the few verifiable measurement. Happiness is all about mindset. And mindsets vary. Someone said this. “A successful man is someone who does whatever the fuck he/she wants between waking up and going to bed.” That statement makes sense to me. And I think money does allow me to achieve that without impacting my family.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">When you think about your job, you have to ask this question; is my salary worth third of my life?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">It’s cute that we all go to work and pretend for 8 hours</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/career/2018/09/25/Almost-Cute.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="It's cute that we all go to work and pretend for 8 hours" /><published>2018-09-25T06:02:18-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-25T06:02:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/career/2018/09/25/Almost-Cute</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/career/2018/09/25/Almost-Cute.html">&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I was looking around the office and found it amusing that everyone was working so hard to create this illusion that what they do matters.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Yesterday, I was looking around the office and found it amusing that everyone was working so hard to create this illusion that what they do matters.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Life Progression as I see it</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/23/Life-Progression-As-I-See-it.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life Progression as I see it" /><published>2018-09-23T16:58:18-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-23T16:58:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/23/Life-Progression-As-I-See-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/23/Life-Progression-As-I-See-it.html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We are born.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Genes you inherited matter. Environments you inherited matter. So if you think about it, it’s all luck in the beginning. You didn’t earn your genes nor did you earn your environment. That’s why we have to have empathy on some folks for both reasons. In my case, the gene part was pretty decent, but I am not so sure about environment part.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Parenting does matter. But we need well balanced parenting. goldie lock of parenting I call it. Too much not good. Too little not good either. What we really need to do as a parent is to pay undivided attention when they ask for it. And help them to become independent. Don’t be a helicopter parent. Don’t do their homework for them. And get off your fucking phone when your kid wants to talk to you once in awhile.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get your kids to love books. Then your parenting is half done. but I am starting to see a pattern where dumb kids will ever like reading books. It just does not excite them. The dumber the kid is the detailed dumb shit they like. Let me explain. Smart kids like dumb toys such as blocks and legos. Dumb kids like detailed toys like video fucking games, robots and shit like that. Books require brain work. And I noticed that kids whom I deem dumb do not like reading books. So I don’t think you can force your kids to love reading books.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you can afford it, give your kids an opportunity to try different things. Some might stick. Over the years, I’ve come to conclusion that you can’t really force your kids to be great at anything; they will have to want it. But they might not find out what they love if they never get exposed to them. But again, your environment comes into picture again. Some parents have time and money to do so and some parents don’t.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These five things are the ones that I firmly believe. And there are some things that I think I should teach my kids about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Race and racism.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finance. Money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">We are born. Genes you inherited matter. Environments you inherited matter. So if you think about it, it’s all luck in the beginning. You didn’t earn your genes nor did you earn your environment. That’s why we have to have empathy on some folks for both reasons. In my case, the gene part was pretty decent, but I am not so sure about environment part. Parenting does matter. But we need well balanced parenting. goldie lock of parenting I call it. Too much not good. Too little not good either. What we really need to do as a parent is to pay undivided attention when they ask for it. And help them to become independent. Don’t be a helicopter parent. Don’t do their homework for them. And get off your fucking phone when your kid wants to talk to you once in awhile. Get your kids to love books. Then your parenting is half done. but I am starting to see a pattern where dumb kids will ever like reading books. It just does not excite them. The dumber the kid is the detailed dumb shit they like. Let me explain. Smart kids like dumb toys such as blocks and legos. Dumb kids like detailed toys like video fucking games, robots and shit like that. Books require brain work. And I noticed that kids whom I deem dumb do not like reading books. So I don’t think you can force your kids to love reading books. If you can afford it, give your kids an opportunity to try different things. Some might stick. Over the years, I’ve come to conclusion that you can’t really force your kids to be great at anything; they will have to want it. But they might not find out what they love if they never get exposed to them. But again, your environment comes into picture again. Some parents have time and money to do so and some parents don’t.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">We are all Dak Prescott</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/sports/2018/09/23/We-Are-Call-Dak-Prescott.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We are all Dak Prescott" /><published>2018-09-23T16:39:18-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-23T16:39:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/sports/2018/09/23/We-Are-Call-Dak-Prescott</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/sports/2018/09/23/We-Are-Call-Dak-Prescott.html">&lt;p&gt;This is Cowboys QB Dak Prescott’s 3rd year. And he is not that good right now. He caught everyone off guard on his rookie year then had a down year last year and he is having a really bad year this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There aren’t that many QBs who can overcome a bad team or a bad management. I guess most of us are Dak Prescott. Again it’s 80/20. And maybe you and I belong in 80. We need a right team. We need a right company. We need a right manager to thrive. We can perform at our highest level but we do need a right environment to do so. So don’t feel bad if you think you are in a rut and not performing as well as you hoped. Maybe you just need a better manager or a better team to thrive in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of us are not Aaron Rogers or Tom Brady and that’s ok.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">This is Cowboys QB Dak Prescott’s 3rd year. And he is not that good right now. He caught everyone off guard on his rookie year then had a down year last year and he is having a really bad year this year.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Homework helps kids and dogs make people happy?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/23/Homework.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Homework helps kids and dogs make people happy?" /><published>2018-09-23T06:34:18-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-23T06:34:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/23/Homework</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/23/Homework.html">&lt;p&gt;There was this article that was questioning dogs make people happy argument. It says something like it’s not dogs that make people happy, but generally happier people get dogs. Think of some reasons why people don’t get dogs. It’s “too much work.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s something interesting to think about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does homework make kids smarter? or smart kids will do a good job on homework? Which one comes first?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homework is something that has never been proven to “help” kids, but it’s one of many shitty things that we “just” do since we’ve been doing it over years. No data. Just fucking gut feeling bullshitism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently I am reading a book called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Superforecasting-Science-Prediction-Philip-Tetlock/dp/0804136718/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1537710531&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=superforecasting+the+art+and+science+of+prediction&amp;amp;dpID=4171glFnKxL&amp;amp;preST=_SY344_BO1,204,203,200_QL70_&amp;amp;dpSrc=srch&quot;&gt;“Superforecasting”&lt;/a&gt; and it’s really eye-opening.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">There was this article that was questioning dogs make people happy argument. It says something like it’s not dogs that make people happy, but generally happier people get dogs. Think of some reasons why people don’t get dogs. It’s “too much work.”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Do people really change ever?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/23/Do-People-Change.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Do people really change ever?" /><published>2018-09-23T06:34:18-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-23T06:34:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/23/Do-People-Change</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/23/Do-People-Change.html">&lt;p&gt;Think about all the people who’ve known for a long time. Time-travel back to your elementary school. Can you think of anyone who was dope back then suddenly is a medical doctor? I couldn’t think of anyone like that. Not even one. But I can think of a few who were bright, but did not turn out so good.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Think about all the people who’ve known for a long time. Time-travel back to your elementary school. Can you think of anyone who was dope back then suddenly is a medical doctor? I couldn’t think of anyone like that. Not even one. But I can think of a few who were bright, but did not turn out so good.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Sunken Cost Fallacy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/22/Sunken-Cost-Fallacy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sunken Cost Fallacy" /><published>2018-09-22T15:09:18-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-22T15:09:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/22/Sunken-Cost-Fallacy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/22/Sunken-Cost-Fallacy.html">&lt;p&gt;I am starting to wonder if I am sticking with my career due to this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.com/capital/story/20180914-the-trick-to-learning-when-to-cut-your-losses&quot;&gt;“sunken cost fallacy”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If in doubt, Everett recommends reflecting on the entire chain of decisions that has led to where you are now, and considering the counterfactuals – in other words, what’s true and not true, a reality check.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“If presented with the same choice again, would I make the same decision? If not – why not?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;So, it’s a simple idea, with global ramifications. And ultimately, it all goes back to the first lesson of gambling. Any good poker player knows when to fold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I am starting to wonder if I am sticking with my career due to this “sunken cost fallacy”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Does that Translate into Money?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/22/Does-That-Tranlate-into-Money.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Does that Translate into Money?" /><published>2018-09-22T09:48:18-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-22T09:48:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/22/Does-That-Tranlate-into-Money</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/22/Does-That-Tranlate-into-Money.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;time&quot;&gt;Time&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time is the single most important asset you have. Everyone gets 24 hours day. It’s up to you how you spend it. Do you want to spend it on commute? I personally can’t believe some people are willing to spend 4+ hours on commuting back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So you really have to be mindful on where you spend your time one. So whenever you are about to do something, ask yourself this question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Will this thing that I am about to do be translating into money?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some activities that you can’t fuck with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sleep. The most important activity to have highly functioning brain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Off cycle. You need to do some dumb things between highly active brain sessions. That’s when great ideas come, solutions pop and so forth. So do not feel bad about watching a football game or two. Your brain does need that off cycle to function better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And here are some activities that worth your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reading a book.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learning a new thing.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mastering your craft.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Socializing with people who are smarter than you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And things you must avoid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;social networking garbage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;shopping. (What I wear does impact how I function. If my clothes and shoes don’t fit right, I can’t function at a high level. But do not shop just for the sake of shopping)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Socializing with dumb fucks. You gain nothing out of it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reading news. Now News is just opinions. And it’s so fucking curated to fit your taste by all these ad companies that it’s not even reality. I stay away from News all together.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Time</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Essential Skill: Seeing Patterns</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/22/Noticing-Patterns.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Essential Skill: Seeing Patterns" /><published>2018-09-22T06:54:18-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-22T06:54:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/22/Noticing-Patterns</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/22/Noticing-Patterns.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;patterns&quot;&gt;Patterns&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What if you can pick up patterns that siginals upcoming market collapse?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can make some money off stock market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What if you can pick up patterns that siginal what makes a great athletes?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can make some money off sport betting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;big-data-and-machine-learning&quot;&gt;Big Data and Machine Learning&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Will these two most hyped buzzwords can help me with that? This is something I need to look into. What facinates me about this machine learning is that it still need a guidance of a smart person. At this point, I don’t think machine learning alone can do much; it hasn’t proved that yet. Even Nate Silver missed on Donald Trump election; he didn’t really missed since he was talking about probabilty, not absolute prediction. Right now, these things really keep me up at night. So difficult, so facinating, and so promising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;spelling-bee-and-baby-steps&quot;&gt;Spelling Bee and baby steps&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently my major focus is on figuring out patterns in English words and spellings. I am trying to help my son and daughter better prepared for next year’s spelling bee; my son won his school bee, moved on to county bee and made it to national scrips’s bee competition this year. It’s a small dataset; about 250k in Webster Unabridged. And they don’t change. So it’s a good size fixed dataset I can play with to learn how to figure out patterns from something that seeems no random. I just don’t see how anything can be completely random. We are animals. Animals are mostly predictable and we form habits. That fact has to affect how we speak as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think there is a complete random in life. Just more complex random that few can see.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Patterns</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How do you prove that you are smart? And does it really matter?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/22/How-Do-You-Prove-that-You-Are-Smart.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How do you prove that you are smart? And does it really matter?" /><published>2018-09-22T06:08:18-07:00</published><updated>2018-09-22T06:08:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/22/How-Do-You-Prove-that-You-Are-Smart</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/life/2018/09/22/How-Do-You-Prove-that-You-Are-Smart.html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-do-you-prove-that-you-are-indeed-smart&quot;&gt;How do you prove that you are indeed smart?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is how I measure if someone is smart or not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;education credentials: The better education you have, the more benefit of doubt I would give you. I would say some shit like ‘he does dumb things, but he did go to Havard. What the fuck?’ Not a requirement, but it helps shallow people like me. And there are tons of us.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Well spokeness. From my experience, when I know my shit inside out, I speak well. I stumble on things I am not too familiar with. So learn to speak well. Stop with fillers already. um.. um.. um..&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Signal and Noises. I could care less on what I call “Jeopardy” knowledge. You know one of those who knows a lot of shit on a lot of things. That can impress some folks at parties. Nothing more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;money-and-fame-sticking-with-verifiables&quot;&gt;Money and Fame. Sticking with verifiables.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people think their kids are smart. Not true. 80/20 rule applies to every fucking thing in life. Most likely than not, your kids belong in 80, not 20.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Smart ones read a lot. No exception. It’s not just the act of reading that make them smart. It’s the end result that helps them become smarter. Books do make you smart. Period. Some people always say this shit when someone talks about how harmful digital consumption is. Their argument is always people used to say the same shit about reading books. So you think checking facebook and reading a book are the same thing? That tells everything I need to know about your brain capacity. I buy a lot of books. Fortunately my son reads a lot. And the funny thing is the more you read, the faster you can read. These sentences get processed quicker and quicker. You start forming these patterns of words, your brain start grouping them together. Things get processed in chunks. Read books. Some authors, philosophers pondered these ideas throughout their lives. You are stealing them in a few day. And it costs you around $10. The best and the cheapest investment you can ever make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I thought about where my career is at this point alot. I do not have that much time left when it comes to career. I am quickly becoming that person that I used to hate when I was a junior developer; old and difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I think constant self-assessment is very import. It’s tough and sad sometimes. But you have to do it. And you will have to pivot if you are not reaching your goal. I don’t even know what my goal is. And now I am thinking my goal was all messed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, goal needs to be verifiable. And in this world, there should be only two goals in life; money and fame. And probably the two go in hand in hand. If I do my best work, money will just fall onto my laps. It sounds virtuous, but does that really happen?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Money is money. Doesn’t matter where and how you make it. But I want to make it the right way. The right way for me would be not to screw other human beings. I do not want to make someone work 24 hours a day away from his family to make myself rich. And I could care less about fame. So my goal is set. Making as much money as possible. So how do I achieve that goal?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you go back to where you are right now. Continue doing what I am doing will help me achieve that goal? Keeping my head down coding away? The answer is no. Then I need a plan. How am I planning to achieve my goal of making lots of money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also need to take any ambiguity out of my goal. What’s “lots of money” for me? At this point, if I can pull in my salry level or little higher without doing my current work, that sould be a good smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then think about risk. How much risk are you willing to to take? That’s always important. But there are different types of risk. Dumb risk and smart risk. Dumb risk would be something that you would put in a lot of money then lose everything and be on debt. Smart risk would be something that you can learn something out of and cause minimal financial risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently thinking a few things. Some are low risk and some are high risk. I am thinking about doing low risk things and put that money into higher risk things to balance it out. And I am trying to make most of things to be as low risk as possible. How? I will delegate most work to machine. I am not into working night and day; but I do it a lof of when it is about my own project. So I get it when people say you start working alot when it’s your own business. I sorta see myself doing that as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;went-sideways-again-back-to-the-point&quot;&gt;Went sideways again. Back to the point&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always think I am smart enough. But looking around, I can’t really back it up. The only thing I am clinging on was that IQ test that I took when I was in middle school which I scored 145. But I did not go to elite school. Never really studied hard. Schools always bored me for some reason. So sometimes I need to wake the hell up and realize that my career is shit. But then again. Isn’t most people’s career the same? When I meet people now, I can see so clearly. And they are where they are because how they are. And they will never get anywhere higher than where they are. The system is alwasy triangle shaped. There are less as you move up. That’s why most people’s career gets suck at middle manager position and ends there. I don’t have what it takes to even get there. I am just not kiss-assy enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do not want to wonder on my deathbed if I could’ve done better. Before it is too late, I want to find out if I am really smart. And I came to a conclusion that only money that prove that I am or not. I am an engineer and money is the only verifiable validation of being smart.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">How do you prove that you are indeed smart?</summary></entry></feed>